Guide to the Papers of George L. Mosse (1918-1999), 1780-2001 AR 25137 / MF 671
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series VIII: Offprints, 1780-1998; 8 linear feet
  This series contains a collection of off-prints that George L. Mosse gathered throughout his long academic career. The off-prints, photocopied chapters of books, and some conference papers were sent or presented to George L. Mosse; they often carry a dedication by the author. Some of the off-prints are also annotated by George L. Mosse. His insertions and some photocopies were kept with the offprints as well. The topic of the off-prints and various conference papers basically covers the main interests of George L. Mosse, i.e. different aspects of European, German, and Jewish history and culture, questions of social hygiene, sexuality, etc.
  - 1) European History and Culture, 1930-1997
    - Ackerknecht, Erwin H., 1956 - 1990 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Adam - Armstrong, 1959 - 1981 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Baker - Battenhouse, 1945 - 1962 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Baron, Hans, 1938 - 1992 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Baumer - Bernal, 1937 - 1992 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Binion - Burrell, 1948 - 1993 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Cahill - Caspari, 1935 - 1982 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Church - Cohen, Richard I., 1951 - 1991 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Cohen, William - Curtis, 1955 - 1989 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Dasnabedian - Dijk, 1971 - 1987 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Drescher - Dupront, 1970 - 1991 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Edson - Epstein, 1960 - 1970 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Ferguson - Fox, 1959 - 1990 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Gargan - Green, 1952 - 1985 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Grendler - Grossberg, 1956 - 1989 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Harbison - Herding, 1931 - 1993 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Hexter, J. H., 1956 - 1991 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Hill - Holquist, 1951 - 1997 (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Howe, 1954 (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Hoyt - Hutton, 1954 - 1968 (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Jacob - Jaeger, 1930 - 1966 (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Kammen - Kelley, 1954 - 1982 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Kingdon, Robert M., 1957 - 1982 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Kirby - Kren, 1939 - 1987 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Lachance - Lunn, 1960 - 1978 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - MacDonald - Mazower, 1957 - 1997 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - McCaffrey - Mosse, W. E., 1950 - 1987 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Mousnier - Murray, 1956 – 1976 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Nugent - Orsini, 1956 - 1971 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Paret - Petrovich, 1956 - 1996 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Pocock - Popkin, 1951 - 1968 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Post - Quinlan, 1965 - 1979 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Rabinbach - Ravid, 1955 - 1985 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Rearick - Ritter, 1953 - 1989 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Roberts - Rowen, 1939 - 1983 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Sabean - Schilfert, 1952 - 1991 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Schorske - Senn, 1955 - 1987 (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Setton - Smith, Lacey B., 1955 - 1978 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Smith, Goldwin - Soloway, 1940 - 1979 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Solt - Stuurman, 1954 – 1994 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Tarrow - Thadden, 1967 - 1993 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Thayer - Trinterud, 1941 - 1996 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Valensise - Verschuuren, 1986 - (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Weimann - Williams, 1958 - 1985 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Willis - Woolf, 1940 - 1977 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Yahil - Zeeveld, 1946 – 1990 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Unknown (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - 2) German history and culture, 1780-1998
    - Abbt-Aydelotte, 1937-1997 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Bauemer-Barkin, 1969-1992 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Baron-Beller, 1939-1995 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Benjamin-Bittel, 1931-1996 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Blessing-Brickmann, 1957-1994 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Carmon-Carsten, 1943-1981 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Clark-Ernst, 1948-1983 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Farmer-Fishman, 1965-1995 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Forell-Fritzsche, 1822-1995 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Gay-Graff, 1939-1992 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Grimm/1, 1966-1974 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Grimm/2, 1975-1989 (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Groening-Heller, 1950-1992 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Henning-Hermand, 1962-1996 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Herrmann-Hirsch, 1967-1991 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Hoehn-Horne, 1940-1997 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Iggers-Juenger, 1930-1998 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Kamm-Kater, 1957-1987 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Keck-Kulka, 1947-1992 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Lamberti – Linke, 1962 - 1991 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Linse – Lutz, 1970 - 1997 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Mack – Megill, 1967 - 1995 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Mergner – Muessener, 1949 - 1988 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Nell – Nipperdey, 1967 - 1983 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Nollendorfs – Orr, 1976 - 1984 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Paret – Pross, 1967 - 1996 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Puhle, Hans-Juergen, 1964 - 1980 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Rabinbach – Runge, 1943 – 1988 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Sabean – Schulze, 1956 - 1986 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Schorske – Skidmore, 1935 - 1993 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Snell – Stanitzek, 1956 - 1988 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Steinmaetz – Trommler, 1960 – 1988 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Ulbricht – Zelinsky, 1951 – 1995 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Unknown (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - 3) Jewish History and Culture, 1815-1998
    - Abrahamsen – Avni, 1963 - 1997 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Bacharach – Baranay, 1955 - 1988 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Baron – Bechtel, 1976 - 1997 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Bein, Alex, 1958 - 1965 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Beller – Berghahn, 1960 - 1998 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Berkowitz – Bornstein, 1933 – 1966 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Borowitz – Brann, 1915 - 1962 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Breidecker – Busi, 1977 - 1994 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Carsten – Cohen, 1977 - 1992 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Davis – Engel-Holland, 1969 - 1995 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Fehervary – Freeden, 1988 - 1998 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Freund – Funkenstein, 1934 - 1993 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Gay – Gilman, 1975 - 1989 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Goldin – Groth, 1924 – 1994 (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Habermas – Henriques, 1963 – 1990 (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Herrmann – Hyman, 1815 – 1985 (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Idel – Jaeger, 1915 – 1987 (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - Kaiser – Kolatt, 1969 – 1997 (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - Komperts – Kwiet, 1962 – 1994 (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - LaCapra – Lessing, 1963 – 1998 (Box 82, Folder 21)
    - Levin – Lipset, 1968 – 1998 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Loewenberg – Luxner, 1968 – 1994 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Margaliot – Mendes-Flohr, 1966 - 1992 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Meyer – Mork, 1968 - 1998 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Moro – Mueller, 1976 - 1994 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Nadler – Orbach, 1978 - 1997 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Paucker – Pulzer, 1954 - 1997 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Rabinbach, Anson, 1976 - 1988 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Ravid – Reinharz, 1978 - 1989 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Repgen – Ruppin, 1919 - 1983 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Salluste – Schorske, 1947 - 1996 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Schulin – Simon, 1964 - 1996 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Sivan – Soeder, 1972 - 1995 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Sorkin – Szajkowski, 1975 - 1999 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Tal, Uriel, 1969 – 1976 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Talmon, 1972 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Toch – Tzahor, 1972 – 1982 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Uran - Volkov, 1972 – 1988 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Wasserstein – Wilson, 1962 – 1990 (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Wisse – Wormser-Migot, 1962 – 1989 (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Yahil – Young, 1992 – 1993 (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Zapponi – Zweig, 1975 – 1996 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Unknown (Box 83, Folder 23)
  - 4) National socialism and right movement, 1921-1998
    - Ackermann-Ascheim, 1965-1975 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Bassin-Boergo, 1921-1995 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Bolaffi-Bruck, 1942-1991 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Cabral-Castellan, 1962-1998 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Delzell-Ebbinghaus, 1941-1997 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Feingold-Friedrich, 1946-1993 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Genitle, 1975-1997 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Gilbert-Grossman, 1972-1996 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Hachmeister-Hoskins, 1958-1995 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Jacobitte-Kater (1969-1972), 1933-1980 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Kater, 1981-1995 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Kedourie-Krieger, 1960-1996 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Lachance-Luschnat, 1969-1991 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Mason-Melograni, 1933-1976 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Michaelis-Mommsen, 1972-1994 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Neumann-Ottnad, 1954-1981 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Paret-Pierre, 1937-1993 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Pinto-Proctor, 1963-1998 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Radetti-Repgen, 1959-1997 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Rietzler-Ryszka, 1969-1987 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Salomone-Schweitzer, 1966-1989 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Seidel-Sorvig, 1958-1954 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Spackman-Spini, 1960-1986 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Spode-Sznajder, 1971-1994 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Tal-Turner, 1976-1995 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Unger-Venturi, 1965-1993 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Viereck-Vondung, 1952-1996 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Wagner-Woolf, 1958-1993 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Yack-Zitelmann, 1988-1996 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Unknown (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - 5) Sexuality, 1901-1998
    - Bettelheim-Curran, 1972-1998 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Drake-Duyves, 1980-1989 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Fadermann-Grossmann, 1975-1998 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Hekma-v.Hull, 1922-1988 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Kern-Murard, 1974-1992 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Nye-Summer, 1952-1991 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Tourney-Whellwright, 1956-1995 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Unknown, 1969-1984 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - 6) World War One, 1915-1995
    - Abraham-Colin, 1919-1984 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Deak-Horne, 1915-1995 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Italiener-Joll, 1917-1972 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Kater, Michael H., 1971-1988 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Kohn-Linse, 1947-1988 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Mackaman-Rutgers, 1982-1995 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Saul-Wollheim, 1965-1990 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Unknown Author (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - 7) World War Two and Holocaust, 1930-1997
    - Ackermann-Ash, 1979-1996 (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Ball-Browning, 1964-1996 (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - Carsten-Ernst, 1950-1992 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Falkenheim-Juenger, 1930-1995 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - Kater-Loewe, 1965-1995 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Marrus-Proctor, 1943-1992 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Renz-Tugel, 1939-1997 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Weinberg-Zuroff, 1967-1994 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Unknown Author (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - 8) Others, 1825-1996
    - Adler – Aubert, 1970 – 1979 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Baird – Burgener, 1953 – 1996 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Canetti – Curtis, 1958 – 1992 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Dascal – Edelmann, 1968 – 1991 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Fellmann – Fisher, 1966 – 1993 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Fogel – Fraser, 1965 – 1991 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Gleason – Gurwitsch, 1935 – 1975 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - van Harten – Hugh, 1959 – 1996 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Ingaro – Jordan, 1946 – 1993 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Kaiser – Kugelmass, 1946 – 1991 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Labedz – Lovejoy, 1935 – 1988 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Marchand – Muller, 1963 – 1989 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - D.H.N. – Naimann, 1966 – 1990 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - O`Brien – Rouanet, 1956 – 1995 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Schalk – Sommerville, 1973 – 1991 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Starr – Swidler, 1912 – 1996 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Tenfelde – Troen, 1972 – 1994 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - Vansina – Wright, 1825 – 1989 (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - Zani – Zarek, 1930 – 1991 (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Unknown (Box 87, Folder 25)